Alumni/ae Records UA023
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Alumni/ae Records
1950 -- 1965
1925 -- 2005
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Alumni Relations
Miller, Russell E.
UA023
9.25 Linear Feet 10 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series: Alumni/ae; and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
This material was collected by Russell Miller while preparing his history of Tufts University, Light on the Hill. All material was arranged by subject and no attempt was made to recreate original order.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains general alumni information, as well as information about alumni councils, alumni days, alumni associations, and homecoming. Materials include photographs, brochures, pamhplets, meeting records, ledgers, and some memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Russell Elliott Miller was a Professor of History, University Historian and Archivist of Tufts University, and author of "Light on the Hill, A History of Tufts College from 1852 to 1952" and the second volume "Light on the Hill, A History of Tufts University since 1952." He was born in Bloomington, Minnesota, on April 25, 1916, to one of the last pioneer families in the Minnesota prairie. His mother spoke Dakota Sioux, which she had learned as a child. He received a B.A. in Education in 1937 and an M.A. in political science in 1939, both from the University of Florida at Gainesville. From 1942 to 1946, he served in the Army Air Corps as an enlisted man, rising to the rank of technical sergeant. Initially with personnel and classification, he was finally assigned to the historical section (intelligence) at the headquarters of the troop carrier command. In 1948 he earned a Master of Arts in history from Princeton University and came to Tufts that same year.
In 1952 he received a PhD from Princeton, and in 1964 Tufts appointed him Professor of History and University Historian and archivist. He taught courses ranging from the history of western civilization to the history of the American frontier. In 1966, he published "Light on the Hill, A History of Tufts College from 1852 to 1952." That year he received the Distinguished Service Award from the Tufts Alumni Association and became an honorary member of Phi Beta Kappa. In 1975 he became the Walter S. Dickson Professor of English and American History and chaired the Department of History from then until 1980. He was voted Emeritus Professor of English and American History in 1981 and received an honorary Doctor of Letters degree in 1983. In 1986, he completed the second volume of Tufts history, "Light on the Hill II, A History of Tufts University since 1952."
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Alumni and Alumni Relations; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards
- Alumni/ae, 1860 -- 1993; 1950 -- 1965; UA023.001; 3.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains general alumni information, as well as information about alumni councils, alumni days, photographs, alumni association information, and homecoming.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Alumni Association memorabilia, 1884 -- 1954; UA023.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Alumni/ae general, 1907 -- 1971; UA023.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association, general, 1863 -- 1986; UA023.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association, seniors awards, 1975 -- 1991; UA023.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association record book, 1860 -- 1920; UA023.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association ledger book, including membership lists, 1861 -- 1912; UA023.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association records, 1920 -- 1933; UA023.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - alumni children, 1943; UA023.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council, 1933 -- 1983; UA023.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council, 1936 -- 1938; UA023.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council, 1941 -- 1951; UA023.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council, 1951 -- 1957; UA023.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council, 1958 -- 1959; UA023.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council, 1958 -- 1959; UA023.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council, 1960 -- 1975; UA023.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council, Tufts service citations, 1970 -- 1983; UA023.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council, continuing education, 1960 -- 1981; UA023.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day, 1904 -- 1964; UA023.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day over 50 years, 1962 -- 1964; UA023.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day, photos, 1958; UA023.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day, photos, 1960; UA023.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day, photos, 1961; UA023.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day, 1962 -- 1964; UA023.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day, 1965; UA023.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day, 1966; UA023.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day, 1967; UA023.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day, 1968; UA023.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day, 1969 -- 1976; UA023.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Alumni dramatics, 1929 -- 1938; UA023.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Leaders Symposium, 1968 -- 1970; UA023.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Office, 1928 -- 1965; UA023.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Alumni opinion survey (1), 1975; UA023.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Alumni opinion survey (2), 1976; UA023.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Alumni professorships, 1904 -- 1954; UA023.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Relations, Office of, 1984 -- 1985; UA023.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Homecoming, 1927 -- 1986; UA023.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Relations, Office of, Tuftonia's Day/Tuftonia's Week, 1985 -- 1993; UA023.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Homecoming committee, 1964 -- 1965; UA023.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Homecoming, 1966 -- 1967; UA023.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Dental School, war history, 1941 -- 1944; UA023.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Jackson Association of Tufts Alumnae (1), 1963 -- 1970; UA023.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Jackson Association of Tufts Alumnae (2), 1966 -- 1972; UA023.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Publications, Alumni Bulletin, 1936 -- 1937; UA023.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Publications, Tufts Alumni Review, 1943 -- 1951; UA023.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Publications, Tufts College Graduate, 1910 -- 1925; UA023.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Alumni Office, war history, 1940 -- 1948; UA023.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Alumni scholarships, 1900 -- 1977; UA023.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Alumni Weekend, 1964 -- 1990; UA023.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae, general, 1905 -- 1977; UA023.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Assocation of Tufts Alumnae (1), 1905 -- 1924; UA023.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae (2), 1910 -- 1923; UA023.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae, by-laws, charter, constitution, 1908 -- 1958; UA023.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae, board meetings, 1900 -- 1980; UA023.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae, records of meetings, 1923 -- 1950; UA023.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Alumni Council, Tufts traditions tour, 1959 -- 1973; UA023.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Association of Tufts Alumni, distinguished service awards, 1953 -- 1991; UA023.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Famous alumni/ae, 1925 -- 1989; UA023.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Alliance of Washington, D.C., 1993; UA023.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club, Inc., 1989; UA023.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Boston, 1909 -- 1980; UA023.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Chicago, 1925 -- 1929; UA023.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Cleveland, 1917 -- 1918; UA023.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Connecticut, 1909 -- 1957; UA023.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Constantinople, 1921; UA023.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Denver, 1960; UA023.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Detroit, 1924; UA023.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Fall River, 1916; UA023.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Knoxville, 1938; UA023.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Lawrence, 1910; UA023.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Long Island, 1972; UA023.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Mystic Valley, 1939 -- 1943; UA023.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Neponset Valley, 1973; UA023.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of New Hampshire, 1923 -- 1973; UA023.001.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of New York, 1909 -- 1968; UA023.001.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of North Shore, 1951 -- 1959; UA023.001.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Philadelphia, 1910 -- 1973; UA023.001.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Philadelphia, 1909 -- 1915; UA023.001.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Portland, 1921; UA023.001.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Puget Sound, 1917 -- 1935; UA023.001.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Rhode Island, 1973; UA023.001.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Rochester, 1938; UA023.001.007.00029 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Southeastern New England, 1930; UA023.001.007.00030 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Southern California, 1923 -- 1966; UA023.001.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Vermont, 1915 -- 1973; UA023.001.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Washington, 1923 -- 1973; UA023.001.007.00033 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Club of Worcester (photo), 1955; UA023.001.007.00034 (Box 7)
    .
  - Handbook for club officers, 1957; UA023.001.007.00035 (Box 7)
  - Tufts College Teachers Association, 1916 -- 1962; UA023.001.007.00036 (Box 7)
- Additional accessions, 1925 --2005; UA023.002
  - General; Alumni Association misc. pamphlets, brochures of class reunions, 1961 -- 1993; UA023-001 (Box data_value_missing_0af3f7ba3c58e223fbe07bc9e87379d8, Box 1)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae records, publications, and photographs, 1925 -- 2005; UA023-002 (Box data_value_missing_65a71f1b586eb2b14bcecedb8e01bd80, Box 2)
  - Association of Tufts Alumnae binder and Alumni Hall serving tray, 1955 -- 1968; UA023-003 (Box data_value_missing_2f9562bc2d7beebaa8efbe4242f7c195, Box 3)